<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Rinocloud</title>
 <link href="http://rinocloud.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://rinocloud.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-02-08T11:36:51+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://rinocloud.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Eoin Murray</name>
   <email>eoin@rinocloud.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>What our market is telling us </title>
   <link href="http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/26/what-our-market-is-telling-us.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-26T17:34:57+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/26/what-our-market-is-telling-us</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-feedback&quot;&gt;Getting feedback&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked at the research on the explosion of data and the challenges it was causing. Then we went straight to researchers at the coal face and looked for their opinions and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through friends and colleagues we managed to put together a pretty comprehensive email list of researchers/PhD students in over 10 different colleges/research institutes around the world. We wrote emails to each telling them what we were up to and asking for help. First we asked them to fill in a simple 2 minute survey and secondly if any were were interested, would they mind giving up some of their valuable time to test software for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;80% of those surveyed replied, including nearly 300 offering to test the software for us because they said there was such a need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/9p1s3tx.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s share the results of the survey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We asked how people currently managed their data storage. 80% used a combination of Dropbox, Google Drive and One Drive combined with local storage and USB sticks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We asked how people shared data with other team members. 82% said through personal Dropbox files, through email and by sharing USB sticks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We asked some questions about what lab automation software and what data analytics software they were using AND how they configured this software to manage data from their experiments. Over 90% of those surveyed used Labview, Matlab, Pytnon, R, Origin, Excel. Of those 95% would have used drivers or ‘hacked’ the software in those applications to configure. Nearly all still had to do some cutting and pasting or dragging and dropping to move data back and forth from the storage system. Approx. 3% had coding skills and would have used programming languages such as Python to try and seamlessly link between their lab software and storage.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a saying: you hear what you want to hear. We were hearing what we wanted to hear from the survey because it all resonated with our own experiences and provided justification for what we set out to build. So to get more of a reality check we also interviewed 50 of the group surveyed. These interviews ranged from 10 minutes to 2 hours. The interviews convinced us that we were dealing with a real problem in the scientific research community. The way data was being handled was not up to scratch. Millions was being spent on the best lab equipment, the best lab automation software to carry out the best experiments possible. But data management was not keeping up. There is a smorgasbord of different ad hoc approaches for storing, managing, sharing and searching scientific data. The problem is hassle, time lost, inefficient use of resources. As more and more data is produced the problems are getting worse. Well that’s what we’re telling ourselves anyway and it’s what our friends and colleagues are experiencing. And our beta users are saying that Rinocloud is a gift that keeps on giving. Time will tell!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fin is a founder of Rinocloud. With a career in banking, software, greentech and research, he is a veteran of many data management campaigns. And has the scars and war stories to prove it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The start of RinoCloud </title>
   <link href="http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/25/the-start-of-rinocloud.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-25T17:34:57+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/25/the-start-of-rinocloud</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-happens-when-scientists-get-together&quot;&gt;What happens when scientists get together?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rinocloud is a team of physicists, biologists, chemists, environmental scientists, electronic engineers and programmers from the University of Cambridge, the University of Oxford, University of Granada and the Tyndall National Research Institute. Team members have access to some of the best labs in the world with some of the most sophisticated instrumentation and lab automation software available. Yet we still found ourselves wasting valuable time trying to figure out optimum ways to manage data being generated from our experiments and simulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take experiments, for example. Instrument software has to be configured to generate the data. This has to be interfaced to lab automation software for data analysis. The data in turn has to be configured and formatted for saving in folders in local workstations and servers - and then copied to generic cloud storage, mainly Dropbox and Google Drive. Add to this the time needed to pull all the data back from the cloud, organise it with locally stored data and then format it again so that it can be analysed by local applications. It’s not efficient!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rinocloud-scientists-data-hub&quot;&gt;Rinocloud: scientists data hub&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/rinocloud/static/diagram.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A seamless storage hub for scientific data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloud based that can be searched, shared and secured the way scientists need it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrates with incumbent systems; lab automation and data analysis software.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built on the user familiarity of generic solutions such as Dropbox and Google Drive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notebook, plotting, collaboration features intrinsic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up in minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we specced and built the software based on a minimalist view of what was the Most Viable Product. We asked colleagues and friends to comment and give feedback. Three hundred volunteered to beta test for us. We now have the software running in Cambridge, Tyndall, MIT, Oxford and in universities in Spain and Japan. Not only is it working - it’s exceeding expectations and scientists are clamouring to get access. It’s solving  problems that our users struggle with every day. It’s dealing with inherent inefficiencies that cost projects, funders and labs money; through inefficient use of researchers time; through less than optimal collaboration; through data getting lost or deleted; through not meeting audit and regulator standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s helping sweat lab assets by getting the most out of investment in personnel and equipment – by efficiently organizing their outputs – data. It’s meeting funders needs for audit ability. It’s meeting regulators needs for open access standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the coming weeks we will be significantly increasing the numbers of beta users. We’re trying to get a cross section of different scientific disciplines and we’re looking for experimentalists and theorists. If you want to try the software just enter your email details and as soon as a slot opens up we’ll email you with instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Helena is an Environmental scientist and graduate of the University of Granada and ex Institute of Water. She is one of the founders of Rinocloud. She’s managed large multidisciplinary projects, lots of PhDs and postdoc teams and learned to deal with the lots of different ways they manage their data.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why I left my PhD at Cambridge to start Rinocloud</title>
   <link href="http://rinocloud.com/blog/2016/01/18/why-i-started-rinocloud.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-18T07:34:57+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://rinocloud.com/blog/2016/01/18/why-i-started-rinocloud</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-left-my-phd-and-set-up-rinocloud&quot;&gt;I left my PhD and set up Rinocloud&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked hard to get into Cambridge to do my PhD. I became a EU Marie Curie Fellow of Physics, was assigned two of the top scientists in the world in Semiconductors as supervisors. I got to work in the Cavendish lab. My peers were some of the best researchers in the world in their field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-why-did-i-leave&quot;&gt;So why did I leave?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love science: The investigation; the analysis. I enjoy the carrying out of experiments; watching the data being generated; the anticipation of what I might find. But data management is a pain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The corralling of the data after it is generated;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The busy unproductive work of preparing it and getting it organised for analysis;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The code hacking needed to configure lab information systems and integrate instruments;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cutting and pasting of long laborious files into generic storage systems;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The inefficient sharing of data via files, memory sticks and email;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the dreaded search for data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-straw-that-broke-the-camels-back&quot;&gt;The straw that broke the camel’s back&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A colleague working on another project left and my team were asked to take over his research. It took us 6 weeks to figure out where his data was and what it contained. The data management was so bad that we could not verify his results and the project could not continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked to see if there was system out there that would organise my data for me, and plug into all the different programs I use. I couldn’t find anything. If I had these problems I figured researchers the world over were experiencing the same. After a lot of research on the market, I dropped out and am now doing a start up building a SaaS solution for every day scientific data management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team – all scientists and programmers - have built and rolled out an MVP/prototype that deals with many of the issues we live with as researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-looks-like-weve-hit-a-chord&quot;&gt;It looks like we’ve hit a chord.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends and colleagues in some of the top research universities in the world have encouraged us to build and keep building the product. Many are using and testing in closed beta. More have signed up to be rolled out as testers. We have a rigorous feedback loop. The discipline needed now from us is to make sure we keep to a well defined roadmap because we’re getting so many suggestions for improvements and new features to solve the myriad of everyday data management problems researchers are experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the problems we’re solving are resonating. Hence the big opportunity to build a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to talk to anyone about data, science, starting a business and share war stories and insights. We’re accelerating releases of beta versions now and have plugins for Python, Matlab and Labview. Data being poured into the Rinocloud hub has full metadata and we have a clever search facility. Rolling out are auto plotting of data, an electronic notebook and a whole raft of collaboration features. Take a look. Sign up. We’re looking for feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eoin is a founder of Rinocloud. He’s worked in Tyndall and Cambridge labs. He’s a physicist and programmer. He’s generated a lot of data so far in his life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>API explorer</title>
   <link href="http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/12/api-explorer.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-12T17:34:57+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/12/api-explorer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;rinocloud-api-explorer-for-developers&quot;&gt;Rinocloud API explorer for developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took advantage of the awesome open source &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dropbox/dropbox-api-v2-explorer&quot;&gt;dropbox api explorer&lt;/a&gt;.
We have been using it internally for a few weeks to test the rinocloud api.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its live now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://rinocloud.github.io/rinocloud-api-explorer/&quot;&gt;https://rinocloud.github.io/rinocloud-api-explorer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Saving data with numpy vstack</title>
   <link href="http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/12/saving-data-with-numpy.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-12T17:34:57+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://rinocloud.com/jekyll/update/2016/01/12/saving-data-with-numpy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Say we have a numpy array we want to save to a file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;savetxt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&#39;test.txt&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will give a file with the following content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
0.0e+00
8.0e+00
7.0e+00
6.0e+00
1.0e+01
7.0e+00
9.0e+00
9.0e+00
0.0e+00
3.0e+00
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is great, the column based representation means that its easy to import into csv compatible programs
like excel, LabView, Matlab and Origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what happens when we want to save two or more arrays together and make sure the file is still easily importable
into different programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we just use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;savetxt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&#39;test.txt&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we get&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
9.0e+00 9.0e+00 4.0e+00 2.0e+00 0.0e+00 8.0e+00 1.0e+01 2.0e+00 1.0e+00 9.0e+00
2.0e+00 3.0e+00 1.0e+00 9.0e+00 2.0e+00 5.0e+00 1.0e+01 2.0e+00 8.0e+00 3.0e+00
9.0e+00 8.0e+00 2.0e+00 7.0e+00 9.0e+00 0.0e+00 6.0e+00 0.0e+00 2.0e+00 3.0e+00
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead lets use &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy-1.10.1/reference/generated/numpy.vstack.html&quot;&gt;numpy vstack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;random_integers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;savetxt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&#39;test.txt&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;vstack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;((&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;test.txt&lt;/code&gt; with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
9.0e+00 2.0e+00 9.0e+00
9.0e+00 3.0e+00 8.0e+00
4.0e+00 1.0e+00 2.0e+00
2.0e+00 9.0e+00 7.0e+00
0.0e+00 2.0e+00 9.0e+00
8.0e+00 5.0e+00 0.0e+00
1.0e+01 1.0e+01 6.0e+00
2.0e+00 2.0e+00 0.0e+00
1.0e+00 8.0e+00 2.0e+00
9.0e+00 3.0e+00 3.0e+00
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is much more portable, and can be imported into programs like excel easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read the file again using numpy into the arrays use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;np&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;loadtxt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&#39;test.txt&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a quick and easy way to get arrays in and out of files from numpy. It keeps the files portable for use with other programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
